A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Business Interests, Series C FA312
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Standard Oil Companies
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil Company - Miscellaneous Material, 1904-1907 (Box 118, Folder 890)
    Archbold reports to John D. Rockefeller on 1907 trial. Starr J. Murphy advice re public relations during trial; recommendation that John D. Rockefeller resign from Standard Oil; John D. Rockefeller suggested it to Archbold, who disagreed. Offers of aid o John D. Rockefeller including skeletons in Judge Landis' closet; suits brought by individuals against Standard Oil. Typed notes on Starr J. Murphy-John D. Rockefeller discussion of origins of Standard Oil. 1905 difficulties in Kansas. Requests for interviews. Standard Oil officials' views re impending suits; building up proof that John D. Rockefeller resigned from all Standard Oil companies except Standard Oil of New Jersey. Re Dr. Bacon's history of Standard Oil. Correspondents include J. D. Archbold, Starr J. Murphy, F. B. Squire, George Rogers, John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Virgil Kline.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil Company - Miscellaneous Material - 1934 Code (Box 119, Folder 0890A)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Anglo-American Oil Company, 1888-1949 (Box 119, Folder 891)
    John D. Rockefeller a large stockholder; his stock vote needed to support management. Very sketchy file; no information re amount of stock; items from World War I. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas M. Debevoise.
    87.1A
  - Standard Oil Companies - Anglo-American Oil Company - English Tax Matter, 1920-1929 (Box 119, Folder 892)
    Thomas M. Debevoise investigates chance of Foundation and General Education Board recovering British income taxes; urges test suit. Boards decide against appeal for refunds.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Atlantic Refining Company, 1919-1942 (Box 119, Folder 893)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. sold his stock; appeals from old employees; complaints against company. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., J. Van Dyke, Thomas M. Debevoise.
    87.1A1
  - Standard Oil Companies - Atlantic Refining Company - J. W. Van Dyke, 1870-1936 (Box 119, Folder 894)
    President of company, friend of John D. Rockefeller; kept John D. Rockefeller posted on company progress.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Atlantic Refining Company - Complaints, 1925-1928 (Box 119, Folder 895)
    N. W. Nethken's complaints about company management; demand for bigger dividends, brushed off by Rockefeller office which supported management. Complaints from L. Abrahams and L. Boreman. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, N. W. Nethken.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Atlantic Refining Company - Complaints, 1917-1928 (Box 119, Folder 896)
  - Standard Oil Companies - American Petroleum Institute, 1919-1953 (Box 120, Folder 897)
    John D. Rockefeller gave Institute $250,000 for research and conservation, 1925; disbursement of John D. Rockefeller gift; printed reports. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., W. C. Teagle.
    87.1A2
  - Standard Oil Companies - American Petroleum Institute - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. February 20, 1923 Letter re 8-Hour Day (Box 120, Folder 898)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. urges Institute to study 8-hour day.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Andian National Corporation, 1924-1933 (Box 120, Folder 899)
    Rockefellers purchase 7/11 of stock in Columbian pipeline company; sold at profit, 1932-1933. Company a Standard Oil of New Jersey subsidiary. Correspondents include Bertram Cutler, John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    87.1An
  - Standard Oil Companies - Continental Oil Company, 1919-1935 (Box 120, Folder 900)
    Comments on company operations; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. owned 900 shares; additional stock held by one of the Rockefeller boards. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Bertram Cutler.
    87.1C1
  - Standard Oil Companies - Crescent Pipeline Company, 1927-1928 (Box 120, Folder 901)
    Liquidated in 1928; appeal for aid from old employees declined. No indication of Rockefeller interest in company. Correspondents include Bertram Cutler, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    87.1C2
  - Standard Oil Companies - Cumberland Pipeline Company, 1912-1935 (Box 120, Folder 902)
    Profit statements; company sold out in 1931; no indication of extent of Rockefeller interest. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, Bertram Cutler.
    87.1C13
  - Standard Oil Companies - Consolidated Oil Company, 1932-1956 (Box 120, Folder 903)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. investment in Sinclair's company, through merger with Prairie Oil and Consolidated. Rental of Rockefeller Center space to Sinclair. Criticism of Sinclair; Rockefellers' refusal to fight Sinclair from within company. Stock held by Rockefeller Center; voted for management. Correspondents include Nelson A. Rockefeller, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    87.1C5
  - Standard Oil Companies - Creole Petroleum, 1940-1955 (Box 120, Folder 904)
    Laurance S. Rockefeller elected a director, 1940; resigned, 1943; information on company activities. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller.
    87.1C6
  - Standard Oil Companies - Galena Signal Oil Company, 1913-1930 (Box 120, Folder 905)
    Rockefellers held minority interest through Standard Oil; no management control. Information on company personnel; adjustment of stock structure. Correspondents include Bertram Cutler.
    87.1G
  - Standard Oil Companies - Humble Oil and Refining Company, 1928-1949 (Box 120, Folder 906)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. interest in 8-hour day. Company growth; place in Standard Oil organization; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. refusal to interfere in management. Winthrop Rockefeller's experience in the field; wartime contributions by company. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, Thomas M. Debevoise.
    87.1H
  - Standard Oil Companies - Humble Oil and Refining Company - 1927 Syndicate (Box 120, Folder 907)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. took $500,000 in Morgan syndicate to float Humble bonds, 1927; profit to him, $9,520; also bought $500,000 of the bonds outright.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Illinois Pipe Line Company, 1924-1930 (Box 120, Folder 908)
    John D. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. were stockholders; received stock from Ohio Oil Company. Company absorbed by Ohio Oil, 1930; no participation in management though Rockefeller interests held 36% of the stock. Correspondents include Willard S. Richardson, Bertram Cutler.
    87.1I
  - Standard Oil Companies - Magnolia Petroleum Company, 1912-1948 (Box 121, Folder 909)
    Starr J. Murphy comments on 1913 anti-trust suit by state of Texas. 1925 merger with Socony. No Rockefeller initiative after 1913. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Starr J. Murphy.
    87.1M
  - Standard Oil Companies - Mississippi River Fuel Corporation, 1928-1929 (Box 121, Folder 910)
    Rockefeller investment in gas pipeline; no management functions. Correspondents include Bertram Cutler, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    87.1M5
  - Standard Oil Companies - New York Transit Company - 1940 Suit, 1940-1943 (Box 121, Folder 911)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Rockefeller Foundation answer to charges of infraction of Interstate Commerce Code by Socony. Judge's opinion. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
    87.1N2
  - Standard Oil Companies - Northern Pipeline Company, 1928-1931 (Box 121, Folder 912)
    Report on financial condition. Correspondents include Bertram Cutler.
    87.1N3
  - Standard Oil Companies - Ohio Oil Company, 1887-1956 (Box 121, Folder 913)
    Friendly relations between John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and president of company, Donnell. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Otto S. Donnell.
    87.1O
  - Standard Oil Companies - Ohio Oil Company, 1933-1936 (Box 121, Folder 914)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Prairie Companies - Merger, 1931-1942 (Box 121, Folder 915)
    Merger of Prairie Oil and Gas and Prairie Pipeline with Sinclair Consolidated Oil, 1937; negotiations preceding merger handled by Thomas M. Debevoise and Bertram Cutler. Details of control with H. F. Sinclair carefully explored. Rockefellers endorsed merger.
    87.1P
  - Standard Oil Companies - Prairie Companies - Merger - Miscellaneous Letters, 1931-1933 (Box 122, Folder 916)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Solar Refining Company, 1932-1961 (Box 122, Folder 917)
    Appeals for aid from former employees. Correspondents include E. L. Hughes.
    87.1S
  - Standard Oil Companies - Southwest Pennsylvania Pipeline, 1913-1932 (Box 122, Folder 918)
    87.1S2
  - Standard Oil Companies - Miscellaneous Court Documents, 1931-1933; 11 items (Box 122, Folder 0918A)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Southern Pipeline Company, 1931-1932 (Box 122, Folder 919)
    87.1S3
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of California - "RKD" File, 1940-1946 (Box 122, Folder 920)
    Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Harold E. Ickes.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of California, 1918-1971 (Box 122, Folder 921)
    Informal contacts between Thomas M. Debevoise and company officers; changes in personnel. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise.
    87.1S4
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of California - Arabian Oil Controversy, 1947-1948 (Box 122, Folder 922)
    Comments on United States investments in Middle East.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of California - Davies-Ickes, 1940-1949 (Box 122, Folder 923)
    Ralph Davies, vice president of company, served during war under Ickes. Failed to get his pre-war position back; Ickes pressed legal suit under GI Bill of Rights. Davies resigned to avoid struggle and publicity. Correspondents include Harold E. Ickes, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Ralph K. Davies.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana, 1908-1932 (Box 123, Folder 924)
    1920 2,900% stock dividend. R. W. Stewart, Chairman of the Board. employee relations; proxy fight; Thomas M. Debevoise negotiations with management. Relations with subsidiaries; employee requests for aid. Rockefeller comments on 50 short history of Company. Report on industrial relations problems. Ex-director Jackson's complaints about President Seebert. Chairman of Board Wilson's 1945 Testimony re Petroleum Resources; Wilson's 1947 Newcomen Society Address. Retirement, death of Seebert. Wilson's articles and addresses in 1950's. Standard Oil improvement under Wilson. Dr. Holland's complaints. The Natural Gas Bill fight; Wilson retirement. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., R. W. Stewart, Edward Seebert, Allan Jackson, Robert Wilson, Laurance S. Rockefeller.
    87.1S5
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana, 1940-1950 (Box 123, Folder 925)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana, 1951-1961 (Box 123, Folder 926)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Industrial Representation Plan, 1919 (Box 123, Folder 927)
    Introduction of plan at Standard Oil of Indiana.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Welfare Work, 1919-1926 (Box 123, Folder 928)
    John D. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributions to Whiting Community House.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Frank Z. Carstens, 1926-1931 (Box 123, Folder 929)
    Illinois critic of company, supported John D. Rockefeller, Jr. in proxy fight.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Stock Purchasing Plan, 1930-1935 (Box 124, Folder 930)
    Thomas M. Debevoise and John D. Rockefeller 3rd comments on Plan.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Suit Against Company, 1933-1936 (Box 124, Folder 931)
    Abortive attempt based on Stewart annuity and a stock deal.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Bruce Johnstone, 1935-1944 (Box 124, Folder 932)
    Friend of Thomas M. Debevoise, a lawyer; his illness; his articles on United States Constitution, labor, the oil industry. Discussion of various aspects of Standard Oil. Material re Chicago Traction reorganization. Leaves Board of Standard Oil of Indiana due to illness.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Cowan Estate, 1927-1944 (Box 124, Folder 933)
    Attempts of relatives of ex-President of Standard Oil to get John D. Rockefeller to help in getting part of Cowan's estate; John D. Rockefeller refused to cooperate.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Pension Plan - Retirement of Employees, 1936-1938 (Box 124, Folder 934)
    Printed material on company's retirement plan.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Dividend Notices, Statements, Meetings, Miscellaneous, 1916-1955 (Box 124, Folder 935)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Pension Plan - Dr. Paul Giddens History, 1948-1981 (Box 124, Folder 936)
    Appointed by company in 1948 to write its history. Question of his treatment of Stewart episode. Information received from Thomas M. Debevoise. John D. Rockefeller, Jr., MacKenzie King.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Blaustein Suit, 1933-1944 (Box 124, Folder 937)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana, 1920-1939 (Box 124, Folder 938)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Robert Black, 1938-1949 (Box 125, Folder 939)
    Black's suit against John D. Rockefeller in connection with Pan American Petroleum Transport Company. Complaints dismissed; Black kept trying in series of suits. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, W. D. Embree.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Senate Inquiry, Teapot Dome, 1925-1930 (Box 125, Folder 940)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s 1928 statements to the press.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Senate Inquiry, Teapot Dome - Memos and Statements, 1928-1929 (Box 125, Folder 941)
    Stenographic account of John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s testimony on Senate stand.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Senate Inquiry, Teapot Dome - Bond Letters, 1928 (Box 125, Folder 942)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s search for Continental Trading Liberty Bonds among Standard Oil companies and Rockefeller Boards and investments; none owned any, including companies in which John D. Rockefeller, Jr. or Boards held investment interest.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Senate Inquiry, Teapot Dome - Letters of Appreciation, 1928 (Box 125, Folder 943)
    Letters commending John D. Rockefeller, Jr. on his appearance before Senate committee.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Senate Inquiry - Proxies - Annual Meeting, 1928 (Box 125, Folder 944)
    Re proxies and 1928 annual meeting; Stewart's decision to hold meeting in spite of John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s opposition; voting shares for all directors except Stewart. Re 1929 annual meeting and proxies; John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s request for proxies to oust Stewart; copy of letter and proxy sent to stockholders. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas M. Debevoise, Bertram Cutler.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Senate Inquiry - Proxies - Annual Report 1929, 1928-1929 (Box 125, Folder 945)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Senate Inquiry - W. W. Aldrich, 1928 (Box 125, Folder 946)
    Preparations for proxy fight; legal opinions; Aldrich's opinions. Correspondents include Winthrop W. Aldrich, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Senate Inquiry - Miscellaneous, 1915-1928 (Box 126, Folder 947)
    Aldrich's letters to stockholders; comments by stockholders and others on Stewart's action and John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s response. Comments on John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s appearance before Senate committee; editorial comment on struggle. Miscellaneous material. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, W. W. Aldrich, Bertram Cutler, John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Teapot Dome Inquiry - Stewart - Miscellaneous, 1925-1929 (Box 126, Folder 948)
    Mainly information to Raymond B. Fosdick from G. M. Cook, Public Relations man at Standard Oil of Indiana re Stewart's plan and attitude. Comments on proxy fight by stockholders and newsman. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, Raymond B. Fosdick, G. M. Cook.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Proxy Fight - John D. Rockefeller-John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Correspondence, 1925-1929 (Box 126, Folder 949)
    John D. Rockefeller statement to press; keeping John D. Rockefeller informed; letters to John D. Rockefeller, Jr. re proxy committee progress. Cables re percentage of proxies obtained; John D. Rockefeller, Jr. happy. Correspondents include Bertram Cutler, W. W. Aldrich, Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Leases Upon Naval Oil Reserves, 1929 (Box 126, Folder 0949A)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Office Correspondence and Memos - Expenses and Bills, 1929 (Box 126, Folder 950)
    Attorneys' fees for aid in proxy fight.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Office Correspondence and Memos - Woods-Chorley Correspondence, 1929 (Box 126, Folder 951)
    Reports on proxy campaign in various states.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Office Correspondence and Memos - Lyman Rhodes Correspondence, 1929 (Box 126, Folder 952)
    Equitable Trust work in proxies; testimonial to John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Office Correspondence and Memos - Ivy Lee Correspondence, 1928-1929 (Box 126, Folder 953)
    Reports on publicity.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Office Correspondence and Memos - Ivy Lee Correspondence, 1929-1930 (Box 127, Folder 954)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Office Correspondence and Memos - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Request to Boards re Continental Bonds, 1928 (Box 127, Folder 955)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. asks Boards and Companies to check for Continental bonds.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Office Correspondence and Memos - A. A. Holland, 1929 (Box 127, Folder 956)
    Complaints about Stewart's engineer's experience.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Proxy Letters - Foreign Letters, 1929 (Box 127, Folder 957)
    87.1S51
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Proxy Letters, 1929 (Box 127, Folder 958)
    Arranged by state, county, anonymous; comments on John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s stand.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Proxy Letters (Alabama-Hawaii), 1929 (Box 127, Folder 959)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Proxy Letters (Illinois-Indiana), 1929-1930 (Box 127, Folder 960)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Proxy Letters (Iowa-Michigan), 1929 (Box 127, Folder 961)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Proxy Letters (Minnesota-New York), 1929 (Box 128, Folder 962)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Proxy Letters (New York-Pennsylvania), 1929 (Box 128, Folder 963)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Proxy Letters (Rhode Island-Wyoming), 1928-1929 (Box 128, Folder 964)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Letters Approving John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s Stand, 1928 (Box 128, Folder 965)
    Received before proxy campaign started.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Letters Approving John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s Stand - Proxy LEtters for Special Meeting, 1928 (Box 128, Folder 966)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Proxy - Appreciation, 1929 (Box 128, Folder 967)
    Letters commending John D. Rockefeller, Jr. on his stand, congratulating him upon victory. Letter from Mrs. J. M. Price, who spoke at stockholders' meeting and assisted Rockefeller cause. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Material from Colonel Wood's Office, 1929 (Box 128, Folder 968)
    Arthur Wood's office handled details of proxy campaign; record of expenses; efforts to obtain proxies. Correspondence re payment to attorney; printed copies of proxy literature. February 20, 1929 copy of Outlook. Photographs of John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Stockholders (Box 128, Folder 969)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Miscellaneous, Documents, Leases, 19 items (Box 129, Folder 0969A)
    Extracts from newspaper comments on proxy fight. Senate hearings on Naval Oil Reserve Leases, 1928.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Newspaper Clippings, 1925-1929 (Box 129, Folder 970)
    Mounted clippings in chronological order.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Newspaper Clippings, 1929 (Box 130, Folder 971)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Newspaper Clippings, 1929 (Box 130, Folder 972)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Newspaper Clippings, 1929 (Box 130, Folder 973)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Newspaper Clippings, 1926-1928 (Box 130, Folder 974)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Newspaper Clippings, 1929 (Box 131, Folder 975)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Newspaper Clippings, 1929 (Box 131, Folder 976)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Statements re Elk Basin Labor Conditions, 1919-1923 (Box 131, Folder 977)
    Letters of comment with acknowledgements, in alphabetical order. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. stand for eliminating 7-day work week, 12-hour day, resulting from R. S. Lynd Survey Graphic article on Elk Basin camp.
    87.1S6
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Statements re Elk Basin Labor Conditions, 1922-1923 (Box 131, Folder 978)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Statements re Elk Basin Labor Conditions - Elk Basin Situation, 1921-1923 (Box 131, Folder 979)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. investigation of conditions, comments on Lynd article. Raymond B. Fosdick orders investigation of camp.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Indiana - Statements re Elk Basin Labor Conditions - Newspaper Articles, 1922-1924 (Box 131, Folder 980)
    Comments on John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s support of 8-hour day.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Kansas, 1931-1939 (Box 132, Folder 981)
    Information on 1932 proxy fight. Rockefellers held no stock in company, stayed outside of conflict. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, E. W. Evans.
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil of Kentucky, 1913-1948 (Box 132, Folder 982)
    Former employees' comments on company. Correspondents include Robert W. Gumbel.
    87.1S7
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil Company of New Jersey, 1918-1938 (Box 132, Folder 983)
    Comments on company; requests from old employees; friendship with company officials. No policy making or control. Tributes to John D. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Nelson A. Rockefeller, Thomas M. Debevoise, Eugene Holman.
    87.1S9
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil Company of New Jersey, 1939-1943 (Box 132, Folder 984)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil Company of New Jersey, 1936-1950 (Box 132, Folder 985)
  - Standard Oil Companies - Standard Oil Company of New Jersey, 1951-1961 (Box 132, Folder 986)
  - Standard Oil Companies, 1912-1913; 2 booklets (Box 133, Folder 0986A)